<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>EMF Films</title>
  <link href="https://emffilms.org/feed/feed.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="https://emffilms.org/films/"/>
  <updated>2024-05-13T13:40:13Z</updated>
  <id>https://emffilms.org/films/</id>
  <author>
    <name>EMF Films Team</name>
  </author>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Dune (1984)</title>
    <link href="https://emffilms.org/films/dune"/>
    <updated>2024-05-30T20:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>https://emffilms.org/films/dune</id>
    <content type="html">
			<p>Thursday 30th May 20:00</p>
			<p>1984 - 2h 20 - 15</p>
			<p>Before Denis Villeneuve there was, well, this.</p>
			<p>David Lunch&#39;s 1984 take on Frank Herbert&#39;s classic. Sometimes surprising, sometimes laughable, sometimes just bizarre. A Duke&#39;s son leads desert warriors against the galactic emperor and his father&#39;s evil nemesis to free their desert world from the emperor&#39;s rule.</p>
		</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Hackers &amp; Q&amp;A</title>
    <link href="https://emffilms.org/films/hackers"/>
    <updated>2022-05-31T20:30:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>https://emffilms.org/films/hackers</id>
    <content type="html">
			<p>Friday 31st May 20:30</p>
			<p>1995 - 1h 41 - 12</p>
			<p>In this geek classic hackers are blamed for making a virus that will capsize five oil tankers.</p>
			<p>Do we even need to write this blurb? Geek classic Hackers returns after four years. Legendary hacker Zero Cool and his friends have been framed by The Plague, who has unleashed a computer virus that could cause an environmental disaster. Pursued by the Secret Service, the gang try to gather the evidence to take The Plague down and stop the virus from unleashing havoc. A bumper-fest of hacking, car chases and double-crossing that has become lore in geek culture. Endlessly quotable and a highlight of EMF 2022.</p>
		</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Micro Men</title>
    <link href="https://emffilms.org/films/micro-men"/>
    <updated>2022-05-31T23:45:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>https://emffilms.org/films/micro-men</id>
    <content type="html">
			<p>Friday 31st May 23:45</p>
			<p>2009 - 1h 25 - Exempt</p>
			<p>The rise and fall of one of the giants of the computer age</p>
			<p>Finally showing at Electromagnetic Field, this cult classic comedy drama looks at the friendship, and then bitter rivalry, between Clive Sinclair and Chris Curry. Armstrong captures the larger-than-life presence of Sinclair in a story of determination, hubris and lots of shouting.</p>
		</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Benn Wiebe &amp; QbagYbbxHc</title>
    <link href="https://emffilms.org/films/qbagybbxhc"/>
    <updated>2022-06-01T20:30:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>https://emffilms.org/films/qbagybbxhc</id>
    <content type="html">
			<p>Saturday 1st June 20:30</p>
			<p>2021 - 1h 25 - 15</p>
			<p>?</p>
			<p>We are not allowed to publicise this but we can say it&#39;s a fantasic, funny satire on mainstream media and politics. Benn Wiebe, who was an associate producer and climate consultant on &quot;Don&#39;t Look Up&quot; will deliver an introductory talk on the role of media in impact campaigns.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;Benn is a SXSW Grand Jury Prize &amp; UNICEF Prize winning, Oscar Shortlisted, Webby nominated producer. He has been a social impact advisor and producer working across film, games and events, with a mission to bridge gaps between story and policy, and ultimately champion vast perspectives to aid social movement. He is the Head of Partnerships for Neon Picturehouse, and Executive Producer &amp; Vice-Chairman of HF Productions. He serves as an Advisor of Think Film, Global Environment Media, Screen South, SIE Society, and Treun House Atelier. Benn also consults on projects from producing Netflix impact campaigns (“Don&#39;t Look Up”, “Breaking Boundaries…), Sony&#39;s Picture This, and SDGs in Action with UN DESA as part of the High Level Political Forum.</p>
		</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>The Rubber-Keyed Wonder</title>
    <link href="https://emffilms.org/films/rubber-keyed-wonder"/>
    <updated>2024-06-01T23:45:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>https://emffilms.org/films/rubber-keyed-wonder</id>
    <content type="html">
			<p>Saturday 1st June 23:45</p>
			<p>2024 - 2h - Exempt</p>
			<p>40 Years of the ZX Spectrum</p>
			<p>The Rubber Keyed Wonder tells the story of the Sinclair ZX Spectrum. This film goes into all the finer details of how and why the ZX Spectrum was created, what impact the computer had as well as the various versions that followed right the way through to the latest iteration of the system with the ZX Spectrum Next.&lt;br/&gt;&lt;br/&gt;A chance to see this brand new documentary before it reaches cinemas.</p>
		</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Colossus: The Forbin Project</title>
    <link href="https://emffilms.org/films/colossus"/>
    <updated>2024-06-02T20:30:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>https://emffilms.org/films/colossus</id>
    <content type="html">
			<p>Sunday 2nd June 20:30</p>
			<p>1980 - 1h 41 - 12</p>
			<p>Thinking this will prevent war, the US government gives an impenetrable supercomputer total control over launching nuclear missiles. But what the computer does with the power is unimaginable to its creators.</p>
			<p>A seventies classic and eerily prescient given the current rise of AI. Thinking this will prevent war, the US government gives an impenetrable supercomputer total control over launching nuclear missiles. But what the computer does with the power is unimaginable to its creators.</p>
		</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Silent Running</title>
    <link href="https://emffilms.org/films/silent-running"/>
    <updated>2024-06-02T22:30:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>https://emffilms.org/films/silent-running</id>
    <content type="html">
			<p>Sunday 2nd June 22:30</p>
			<p>1971 - 1h 30 - U</p>
			<p>In a future where all flora is extinct on Earth, an astronaut is given orders to destroy the last of Earth&#39;s botany, kept in a greenhouse aboard a spacecraft.</p>
			<p>The ultimate solarpunk film? In a future Earth barren of all flora and fauna, the planet&#39;s ecosystems exist only in large pods attached to spacecraft. When word comes in that the pods are to be jettisoned into space and destroyed, most of the crew of the Valley Forge rejoice at the prospect of going home. Not so for botanist Freeman Lowell, who loves the forest and its creatures. He kills his colleagues taking the ship deep into space. Alone on the craft with his only companions being three small robots, Lowell revels in joys of nature. When colleagues appear to rescue him, he realizes he has only one option available to him.</p>
		</content>
  </entry>
</feed>